<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="cinderella_page_0_html">
        <![CDATA[
        <p> L.C. Catalog card number: 65-21556 </p>
        <p><b>THIS IS A BORZOI BOOK, PUBLISHED BY ALFRED A. KNOPF, INC.</b></p>
        <p>Copyright ri J 965 by Bent</p>
        <p><b>All rights reserved.</b> No part of this book may be reproduced in any form without permission in writing from the publisher, except by a reviewer, who may quote brief passages and reproduce not more</p>
        <p>than three illustrations in a renew to be printed in a magazine or newspaper.
        <p>Manufactured in the United Stales of America, and distributed by Random House, Inc.</p>
        <p>Published simultaneously in Toronto, Canada, by Random House of Canada, Limited.</p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="cinderella_page_1_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <p>In the ancient city of <b>Montefiascone</b>, there stood the castle of the <b>Baron of Montefiascone</b>. </p>
    <p>The castle had once been <b>magnificent</b> but now was falling to pieces, all because <b>the Baron</b> thought only of <i>his own pleasure</i>.</p>
    ]]>
    </string>


    <string name="cinderella_page_2_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <p> The Baron\'s two daughters, <b>Tisbe and Clorinda</b>, were just like him. They were frivolous and vain and squandered money on jewels, furs, and fine clothes. </p>
    <p> There came a day when the Baron\'s fortune was all <b>gone</b>.  <i>What to do now?</i> The scheming Baron was not long without a solution. </p>
    ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="cinderella_page_3_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <p>He would marry a rich widow, the mother of gentle Angelina.
    The castle again was filled to overflowing and the eating and dancing
    went on for weeks on end.
    </p>
    <p>When they had finished, the Baron was as
    poor as before.Angelina\'s mother died of a broken heart, leaving her daughter to the
    mercy of <b>Tisbe and Clorinda</b>.
    </p>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_4_html">
    <![CDATA[
        <p>They put her to work in the kitchen <i> making her slave day and night</i>.
          Because her only dress was soon covered with ashes, they called her
           <i><b>Cinderella</b></i>.</p>
        <p>
        One fine morning, there was a knock at the kitchen door and <b> a strange beggar entered.</b>
        <p>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_5_html">
    <![CDATA[
        <p>
        <b>\"Have pity on the poor,\"</b> he said, and gentle Cinderella <i>brought him
        some bread.</i>
        </p>
        <p>
        When Tisbe and Clorinda saw this, they <b>flew into a rage</b> and began to
        beat both the beggar and Cinderella.
        </p>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_6_html">
    <![CDATA[
        <p>The beggar fled.</p>
        <p>
        As he vanished through the door, he called back
        mysteriously, <b>\"Foolish girls, if only you knew who I am!\"</b>
        </p>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_7_html">
    <![CDATA[
<p>
Not far from the castle of <b>the Baron of Montefiascone</b> was the luxurious
summer palace of <b>the Prince of Salerno</b>.
</p>
<p>
The Prince was seeking a bride,
and hearing of the Baron\'s two daughters, he sent courtiers to the castle
of Montefiascone.
</p>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_8_html">
    <![CDATA[
        <p>When they arrived, one courtier stepped forward and announced:</p>
        <p><center><i>The Prince of Salerno is coming to call,</i></center></p>
        <p><center><i>And escort you both to his summer ball.</i></center></p>
        <p><center><i>Tonight is the night when he will decide</i></center></p>
        <p><center><i>Which beautiful lady shall be his bride.</i></center></p>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_9_html">
    <![CDATA[
        Imagine the excitement of Tisbe and Clorinda! They rushed through
        the castle calling, <b>\"Cinderella, fetch our jewels, our perfumes, our silks!
    We must be the fairest of all!\"</b>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_10_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <p>
        As the Prince of Salerno was preparing to leave for the Baron\'s castle,
he lamented
    </p>
    <p>
    <b>\"I am afraid every maiden in this kingdom wants only to
    marry a prince, and would do anything to snare him. But I know how to
    fool them.\"</b>
    </p>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_11_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <p>
        Looking at his valet, he said, <b>\"Since we are the same size, let us exchange
clothes. Then you will ride in the carriage and I will ride your horse.\"</b>
    </p>
    <p>
    And thus they galloped off to the Castle of Montefiascone.
    </p>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_12_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <p>
    The Prince, disguised as the valet, arrived first. He went to the kitchen
door and there saw gentle Cinderella. Cinderella looked at the handsome
valet and fell in love with him at first sight.
</p>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_13_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <p> <b>\"Who are you, sweet maid?\"</b> asked the Prince. </p>
    <p> <b>\"I am only the kitchen wench,\"</b> said Cinderella with a sigh.</p>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_14_html">
    <![CDATA[
        <p><i>\"Not one of the daughters of the Baron of Montefiascone? Where are
they then?\"</i></p>
        <p><b>\"Preparing for the arrival of the Prince of Salerno,\"</b> said Cinderella.
At that moment, a great flourish of trumpets sounded.</p>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_15_html">
    <![CDATA[
        The splendid carriage of <b>the Prince of Salerno</b> drew up to the castle
gate. <b>The Baron of Montefiascone and his two daughters</b> bowed down to
the ground exclaiming,<b> \"Highest of Highnesses!\" </b>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_16_html">
    <![CDATA[
        The false Prince descended from the carriage and said, <b>\"Like a bee in
springtime, I seek the lily or the rose who can bring joy into my life.\"</b>
    ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="cinderella_page_17_html">
    <![CDATA[
    The Baron beamed. <i><b>\"Highest of Highnesses, my daughters are the
choicest blossoms of any garden!\"</b></i>
    ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="cinderella_page_18_html">
    <![CDATA[
        Cinderella, who had followed the false valet, said in a small voice,
<b>\"May I come to watch the ball?\"</b>
    ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="cinderella_page_19_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <p>
    <b>"Back to the kitchen!"</b> the Baron roared.
    </p>
    <p>
    Then he exclaimed, <b>"Let us
be off so the merrymaking can begin!"</b>
    </p>
    <p>
He helped his two daughters into
the carriage of the Prince and they left for the grand ball.
    </p>
    ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="cinderella_page_20_html">
    <![CDATA[
    Poor Cinderella went back to the kitchen and sat near the fire thinking
of the handsome valet. <b>\"Will I ever see him again?\"</b> she said and sighed.
    ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="cinderella_page_21_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <p>
    <b>\"Don\'t cry, Cinderella,\"</b> said a voice.
     </p>
    <p>
    Out of the darkest corner of the
kitchen stepped the strange beggar, this time dressed as a magician. <b>\"I
have returned to take you to the ball.\"</b>
</p>
    ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="cinderella_page_22_html">
    <![CDATA[
    He waved his hand over a pumpkin and transformed it into a golden
coach. Maids then appeared to dress Cinderella in <b>a gown sewn with
gold thread</b>, and shoes covered with diamonds and pearls.
    ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="cinderella_page_23_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <p>
    <b>\"Is this a dream?\"</b> asked the bewildered Cinderella.
    </p>
    <p>
    <b>\"Shh, all this is yours, but only till the stroke of midnight. Remember!\" </b>
And the mysterious beggar led Cinderella to the waiting carriage.
    </p>
    ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="cinderella_page_24_html">
    <![CDATA[
    The ball was the most spectacular event in the history of Montefiascone.
All the maidens of the kingdom were there adorned in their most sump
tuous gowns and most glittering jewels.
    ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="cinderella_page_25_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <b>Who among them would the Prince of Salerno choose as his bride?</b>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_26_html">
    <![CDATA[
        The Baron of Montefiascone and his two daughters did not leave the
ide of the false Prince for a moment. <b>\"See Your Highness,\" </b>said the
Baron, <b>\"there are no roses here more glorious than my daughters.\"</b>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_27_html">
    <![CDATA[
    Just then a golden coach arrived, and out of it stepped the most
beautiful maiden in the world.
Who could she be? Where had she come from?
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_28_html">
    <![CDATA[
    The true Prince, disguised as his valet, came forward. <b>\"Something
about this maiden is familiar to me,\"</b> he said to himself.
Bending low, the Prince asked for the privilege of dancing with her.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_29_html">
    <![CDATA[
    And so Cinderella danced happily all evening with the handsome valet,
without knowing who he really was. But at the first stroke of midnight
she fled, and as she ran away, one of her slippers fell from her foot.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_30_html">
    <![CDATA[
<b>\"What has happened? Why did she run away?\"</b> asked the true Prince,
picking up the slipper.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_31_html">
    <![CDATA[
He called to his valet. <b>\"The ball is over. Bring my carriage. Hurry so
we can overtake the owner of this slipper- the maid who has stolen my
heart.\" </b> And they rushed off.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_32_html">
    <![CDATA[
The mysterious beggar, hidden in the shadows, heard everything.
<b>\"And now to make sure that the Prince will stop at the Baron\'s castle,
and then \.\.\.\"</b>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_33_html">
    <![CDATA[
    The Prince\'s carriage careened through the night, when suddenly a
shadow crossed the road and the startled horses turned the carriage into
a ditch.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_34_html">
    <![CDATA[
Seeking help, the Prince and the valet knocked at the door of a
nearby castle. How surprised they were when the Baron of Montefiascone
appeared to greet them.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_35_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <b>\"Ah!\"</b> the Baron exclaimed, <b>\"the Prince has chosen one of my daughters! Tisbe! Clorinda! Come here! Cinderella, bring our best chair for His
Highness!\"</b>

    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_36_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <b>\"May we try this slipper on your daughters?\" </b> asked the true Prince.
    <b>\"We are searching for its owner. She is the one the Prince will marry.\" </b>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_37_html">
    <![CDATA[
Tisbe tried first, and then Clorinda, but both screeched Hke wounded
crows, because their feet were much, much too large.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_38_html">
    <![CDATA[
Just then Cinderella came in, dragging the chair, and the Prince, seeing
her, said, <b>\"Let us try the slipper on her, too.\"</b>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_39_html">
    <![CDATA[
<b>\"Not on the wench!\"</b> shouted the Baron. But the Prince ignored him
and Cinderella tried on the slipper.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_40_html">
    <![CDATA[
    The slipper fit her foot perfectly!
<b>\"I have found you at last!\" </b> the Prince exclaimed.
<b>\"My handsome valet,\"</b> said Cinderella.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_41_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <b>\"I am not a valet but the real Prince, while that man dressed as the
Prince is simply my valet.\"</b>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_42_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <b>\"Through this masquerade, I have been able to
    tell who is really worthy of becoming the Princess of Salerno. \"</b>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_43_html">
    <![CDATA[
    <b>\"Now, before all of you, I hereby announce that Cinderella will become my bride, and
that the marriage will take place at the Palace of Salerno.\"</b>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_44_html">
    <![CDATA[
And the Prince departed, taking Cinderella with him.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_45_html">
    <![CDATA[
        Royal guests came from every land for the wedding of the Prince and
Cinderella. Even the Baron and his daughters appeared, and as they
kneeled before Cinderella asking her pardon, everyone\'s joy was beyond
description.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_46_html">
    <![CDATA[
<b>\"Virtue always triumphs in the end,\" </b> observed the mysterious beggar,
who in reality was the Grand Magician of Naples and the Prince of
Salerno\'s tutor.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_47_html">
    <![CDATA[
For if it had not been for him, Cinderella would not have married the
Prince of Salerno, and lived happily ever after.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_48_html">
    <![CDATA[
        <b>Gioacchino Rossini (1792-1868)</b> is one of the great Italian operatic composers of the nineteenth
century. CENERENTOLA, Rossini\'s Cinderella, was first performed in Rome in January 25, 1817,
when he was only twenty-five. But it was not his initial effort, for he had composed his first opera at
the age of nineteen. Other popular operas which Rossini wrote are THE BARBER OF SEVILLE and
WILLIAM TELL.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_49_html">
    <![CDATA[
Beni Montresor grew up in Verona, Italy. He has designed for films and theater throughout
Europe. In this country, he made his theatrical debut designing Gian Carlo Menotti\'s THE LAST
SAVAGE for the Metropolitan Opera. His books for children have received wide acclaim.
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="cinderella_page_50_html">
    <![CDATA[
His own books, including <b>THE WITCHES OF VENICE and HOUSE OF FLOWERS, HOUSE OF STARS</b>, have been
on all the best books lists. He has won awards from AIGA and the Society of Illustrators. And this
year, 1965, he was awarded the Caldecott Medal for the best illustrated book of the year for Beatrice
de Reigners\' may I bring a FRIEND?
    ]]>
    </string>
</resources>