<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
<string name="snowwhite_page_0_html">
	<![CDATA[
	Every new generation of children is
enthralled by the famous stories in our Well
Loved Tales series. Younger ones love to
have the story read to them. Older children
will enjoy the exciting stories in an easy- toread text.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_1_html">
	<![CDATA[
Once upon a time, on a cold winter\'s day, as
the snowflakes were falling softly and swiftly, a
Queen sat sewing by her window. As she looked
out, the snow scene was framed, like a picture,
by the black ebony of the window frame.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_2_html">
	<![CDATA[
<p>
As she sewed, the Queen pricked her finger
and three drops of blood fell upon her sewing.
The red of the blood, against the white of the
snow, framed by the black wood of the window
frame, looked so beautiful that she thought, \"Oh
how I wish I could have a child as white as snow,
as red as blood and as black as ebony!\"
</p>
<p>
Now it happened that some time afterwards
the Queen did have a baby daughter whose skin
was as white as snow, whose cheeks were bright
red and whose hair was as black as ebony. The
Queen called her little girl Snow White.
</p>
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_3_html">
	<![CDATA[
<p>
Unfortunately, soon after her child was born,
the Queen died. A year later the King married
again.
</p>
<p>
The new Queen was very beautiful but much
too proud of her own beauty. She could not bear
to think that anyone else might be more
beautiful.
</p>
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_4_html">
	<![CDATA[
The Queen had a magic looking-glass which
hung on the wall. Often she stood in front of it
and, gazing at her own reflection, asked this
question:
\"Mirror, mirror, on the wall.
Among the ladies in this land.
Who is the fairest of them all?\"
The mirror always replied,
\'Thou, O Queen, art the fairest of all!\"
The Queen was always content when she heard
this reply for she knew that the magic mirror 
could speak nothing but the truth.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_5_html">
	<![CDATA[
Meanwhile, Snow White was growing from a
baby into a lovely little girl. By the time she was
seven, with her rosy cheeks and dark, dark hair
against her snow white skin, she was even more
beautiful than the Queen.
Thus it happened that one day, when the
Queen asked her mirror,
\"Mirror, mirror, on the wall.
Among the ladies in this land.
Who is the fairest of them all?\"
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_6_html">
	<![CDATA[
it replied,
\"Among the grown-up ladies tall,
Thou, O Queen, art the fairest of all.
Yet the truth I must speak
and so I do vow.
That the child Snow White is more
lovely than thou.\"
When the Queen heard these words, she was
both shocked and angry. She looked more
closely at Snow White and could not fail to see
her growing beauty. Each day, as she watched
the girl, the Queen\'s anger and jealousy
increased.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_7_html">
	<![CDATA[
At length, the time came when the Queen\'s
envy of Snow White\'s beauty gave her no peace,
by day or by night. Hatred for the child filled
her heart. Then the Queen called one of her
huntsmen and commanded him, \"Take this child
away, deep into the forest and kill her, for I can
no longer bear the sight of her!\"
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_8_html">
	<![CDATA[
The huntsman had no choice but to obey.
Taking Snow White by the hand, he led her far
into the forest. When he stopped and drew out
his knife to kill her, the poor child wept and
begged him to spare her life. Please do not kill
me,\" she pleaded. \"If you will spare me, I shall
go further into the forest and I promise never to
try to return home again.\"
When the huntsman saw the tears on such a
young and beautiful face, he took pity on her.
\"Run away then, my poor child,\" he said, as he
put away his knife. \"The wild beasts will soon
devour the poor child,\" he thought to himself.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_9_html">
	<![CDATA[
When Snow White ran off into the great forest
by herself, she was terrified. She did not know
which way to go, nor yet what would happen to
her. She feared she would meet wild beasts which
would attack her.
She ran on and on, over sharp stones and
round prickly bushes with long thorns. She heard
the roars of wild beasts but, although some
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_10_html">
	<![CDATA[
passed her as she ran, none tried to harm her. By
evening her feet were sore, her clothes were torn
and her arms and legs were scratched by the
thorns.
Just as Snow White was ready to fall down
with weariness, she came to a little cottage, by
the side of a mountain. She knocked on the door
but there was no reply. She tried the door and it
opened, so she went inside to rest.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_11_html">
	<![CDATA[
Everything inside the cottage was small and
neat and clean. A white cloth was spread on the
table. The table was laid with seven little plates,
seven little knives, forks and spoons, and seven
little glasses, all set out in proper order. Against
the wall stood seven little beds, each neatly made
up and covered with a white bedspread.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_12_html">
	<![CDATA[
Snow White was both hungry and thirsty but
she did not want to take anyone\'s supper. So
she ate a little of the food from each plate and
drank a mouthful of wine from each glass.
Then Snow White was so tired that she longed
to sleep. She lay down on the first little bed
but somehow she could not make herself
comfortable. She tried the other little beds but
each one seemed too long or too short, too hard
or too soft. None suited her until she came to the
last one, which felt just right. Soon she was fast
asleep.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_13_html">
	<![CDATA[
Now the cottage belonged to seven dwarfs
who, when it became dark, returned home. They
had spent all day in the mountains, digging for
gold.
As they entered their cottage, each one lit a
candle. By the light of the seven candles, they
could see that someone had been there since they
had left that morning.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_14_html">
	<![CDATA[
The first dwarf cried, \"Who has been sitting
on my chair?\"
The second one asked, \"Who has been eating
from my plate?\"
The third one asked, \"Who has been eating
my bread?\"
The fourth one asked, \"Who has been eating
my vegetables?\"
The fifth one asked, \"Who has been using my
knife?\"
The sixth one asked, \"Who has been using my
fork?\"
The seventh one asked, \"Who has been drinking out of my glass?\"
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_15_html">
	<![CDATA[
Next the dwarfs noticed that their beds were
not as neat as when they had left them. The first
dwarf looked at his bed and cried, \"Who has
been lying in my bed?\"
Then each of the other dwarfs, in turn, looked
at his own bed and cried, \"Who has been lying in
my bed?\"
But when the seventh little dwarf reached his
bed, he found Snow White there, fast asleep.
\"Took who\'s in my bed!\" he called to the others
and they all came running to see
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_16_html">
	<![CDATA[
They lifted their candlesticks high, as they
stood around the bed, gazing at Snow White.
\"What a beautiful child!\" they exclaimed.
As the dwarfs were anxious not to waken the
lovely child who slept so soundly, they tiptoed
away and ate their suppers very quietly. Then
when bedtime came, the seventh httle dwarf
spent an hour in the bed of each of the other
dwarfs, in turn, and so the night passed.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_17_html">
	<![CDATA[
In the morning, when Snow White first awoke
and saw the seven dwarfs, she was rather
frightened. The dwarfs however spoke kindly to
her and asked her name. \"My name is Snow
White,\" she replied.
\"But how did you find our cottage?\" they
asked.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_18_html">
	<![CDATA[
Snow White told them about her stepmother
who had sent a huntsman with her into the
forest, to kill her, and how the huntsman had
agreed to spare her life. \"Then I ran and ran all
day through the forest,\" she continued, \"until I
came to this little cottage.\" When the dwarfs
heard this sad tale they were full of pity for the
little girl. The eldest one told her, \"If you will
look after us, keep our house clean and tidy,
cook and wash and mend for us, you can live
here with us and we shall take good care of you.\"
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_19_html">
	<![CDATA[
\"Oh, you are kind!\" replied Snow White. \"I
shall be glad to do that\"
However, before they left the house, the
dwarfs gave Snow White a warning. \"We are out
all day, working,\" they said, \"and you will be
alone in the house. If your stepmother learns that
you are here, she may come and try to do you
harm. So be sure to let no one into the house
while we are away.\" Snow White promised to
heed their warning
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_20_html">
	<![CDATA[
She was very happy living with the dwarfs.
Every morning they went off to the mountains to
dig for gold. Every evening when they returned
home, she had supper ready for them and the
house was neat and clean. Although Snow White
was alone all day, she did not feel lonely for she
had so many things to do.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_21_html">
	<![CDATA[
Meanwhile the Queen, believing Snow White
to be dead, was quite happy in the thought that
she herself was the most beautiful lady in the
land. It was some time before she bothered to ask
the magic mirror the usual question.
When she did stand before the mirror and said,
\"Mirror, mirror, on the wall.
Among the ladies in this land,
Who is the fairest of them all?\"
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_22_html">
	<![CDATA[
she could not believe her ears when she heard
this reply,
\"Thou, O Queen, art exceedingly fair,
But the truth I must speak
and this I do swear,
Snow White is not dead but living still.
In a little house far over the hill;
And though thou, O Queen,
art certainly fair.
This child\'s great beauty doth
make her more fair.\"
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_23_html">
	<![CDATA[
The Queen\'s jealousy would not let her rest
as long as she knew that anyone was more
beautiful than she was. She determined to
find Snow White and kill her herself.
But how could she do this? She knew that she
must not let Snow White recognise her. Finally,
she decided to disguise herself as an old pedlarwoman who called at people\'s houses, seUing
things from her basket. She dressed herself in old
clothes and changed her face. No one could
possibly have recognised the beautiful Queen.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_24_html">
	<![CDATA[
She then travelled through the forest until she
came to the dwarfs\' cottage by the mountain.
She knocked on the door and shouted, \"Taces
and ribbons for sale! Pretty laces and ribbons !\"
Snow White looked out of the window and
thought to herself, \"What harm can this poor
old woman do to me?\"
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_25_html">
	<![CDATA[
Snow White opened the door and the woman
brought her basket into the cottage. Snow White
chose some pretty pink laces for her stays.
The old woman offered to lace up Snow
White\'s corset, properly, with the new laces.
Snow White, suspecting nothing, agreed. Then
the Queen laced her so tightly that the child could
not breathe, and she fell on the floor as if she
were dead.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_26_html">
	<![CDATA[
In the evening, when the dwarfs returned
home, they were shocked to find their beloved
Snow White lying on the floor as if she were
dead. They lifted her up tenderly and, when they
saw how tightly she was laced, they cut the new
laces. Soon she began to breathe again and
gradually the colour returned to her cheeks.
When the dwarfs heard about the pedlarwoman, they were convinced that she must have
been Snow White\'s wicked stepmother.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_27_html">
	<![CDATA[
The dwarfs warned Snow White again, \"Take
great care and be sure to let no one enter the
house.\"
The Queen hurried back through the forest.
She was filled with joy because, believing Snow
White to be dead, she herself must now be fairest
of all.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_28_html">
	<![CDATA[
As soon as she reached home, she removed her
disguise and stood before her mirror, asking,

\"Mirror, mirror, on the wall,
Among the ladies in this land.
Who is the fairest of them all?\"
You can imagine the rage into which she flew
when the mirror replied,
\"Thou, O Queen, art exceedingly fair.
But the truth I must speak
and this I do swear.
Snow White is not dead but living still.
In a little house far over the hill;
And though thou, O Queen,
art certainly fair.
This child\'s great beauty doth
make her more fair.\"
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_29_html">
	<![CDATA[
So, once more the Queen began to plan how
she might kill Snow White. First, she prepared a
comb which was poisoned. Next, she disguised
herself as a quite different pedlar-woman and
filled her basket with new things to sell.
Again she travelled through the forest until she
came to the dwarfs\' cottage by the side of the
mountain. She knocked on the door and
shouted, \" Cheap wares to sell! Pretty things to
sell!\"
Snow White put her head out of the window.
\"I dare not let you come in,\" she said, \"I have
promised the dwarfs to open the door to no
one.\"
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_30_html">
	<![CDATA[
\"Never mind! You can look, can\'t you\"
replied the Queen, holding up the dainty comb.
It was so pretty that Snow White could not resist
it and she opened the door to the pedlar-woman.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_31_html">
	<![CDATA[
The old woman said, \"You must let me comb
your hair properly for you.\" Snow White agreed
and seated herself on a stool. The Queen then
stuck the comb sharply into Snow White\'s head
so that the poison went into her blood.
Immediately she fell to the floor, as if dead.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_32_html">
	<![CDATA[
Fortunately, it was almost evening and soon
afterwards the seven dwarfs came home. When
they found Snow White once more lying on the
floor, they suspected that her stepmother had been again. They soon found the poisoned comb
and pulled it out. Snow White quickly recovered
and told them what had happened.
Once more the dwarfs talked seriously to her.
They warned her of the wickedness of her
stepmother and begged her never to let anyone
enter the house while they were out.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_33_html">
	<![CDATA[
Meanwhile the Queen
was hurrying through the forest,
muttering to herself, \"Fve killed her
this time! I\'ve killed her this time!\"
On reaching home, she removed her disguise
and stood before the mirror, asking,
\"Mirror, mirror, on the wall,
Among the ladies in this land,
Who is the fairest of them all?\"
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_34_html">
	<![CDATA[
Just as before the mirror replied,
\"Thou, O Queen, art exceedingly fair.
But the truth I must speak
and this I do swear.
Snow White is not dead but living still,
In a little house far over the hill;
And though thou, O Queen,
art certainly fair.
This child\'s great beauty doth
 make her more fair.\"
At these words, the Queen stamped her feet and beat on the looking-glass in her rage. \"Snow
White shall die,\" she vowed, \"even if it costs me
my life!\"
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_35_html">
	<![CDATA[
The Queen knew that it might prove
impossible to persuade Snow White to let her
into the cottage a third time, so she plotted
cunningly.
She took a lovely apple which had one green
cheek and one rosy cheek. It looked so tempting
that anyone who saw it must long to eat it. Then
she put poison into the red cheek of the apple
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_36_html">
	<![CDATA[
while leaving the green side free of poison.
This time, the Queen filled her basket with
apples and disguised herself as a farmer\'s wife.
For the third time, she made her way to the
dwarfs\' cottage and knocked on the door.
\"I am forbidden to open the door to anyone,\"
called Snow White through the window.
\"It\'s all the same to me!\" replied the farmer\'s
wife. \"I only want to get rid of these apples.
Here, I\'ll give this one to you,\" she went on,
holding out the poisoned apple to Snow White.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_37_html">
	<![CDATA[
\"I dare not take it,\" replied Snow White,
shaking her head.
The farmer\'s wife laughed pleasantly. \"Are
you afraid that it\'s poisoned?\" she joked.
\"Look, I\'ll cut it in two and we shall each eat
half.\" This she did, holding out the rosy half of
the apple to Snow White and biting into the
green half herself.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_38_html">
	<![CDATA[
Snow White longed to eat the rosy half of the
apple, which looked so tempting. When she saw
the woman happily eating one half of the apple,
she thought there could be no harm in eating the
other half herself. So she took the rosy half of
the apple and bit into it. No sooner had she done
so than she fell down dead.
The Queen laughed a horrible laugh and cried,
\"This time the dwarfs won\'t waken you!\"
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_39_html">
	<![CDATA[
Then the Queen returned to her palace and
asked her mirror,
\"Mirror, mirror, on the wall.
Among the ladies in this land,
Who is the fairest of them all?\"
At long last it answered,
\"Thou, O Queen, art the fairest of all!\"
Thus the jealous Queen was finally content.
When the dwarfs returned home in the
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_40_html">
	<![CDATA[
evening, there lay Snow White on the floor, no
longer breathing. Yet they still hoped that they
might be able to revive her. They unlaced her
stays, combed her hair and washed her face, but
they could not And how she had died.
The dwarfs were heart-broken. They stood
round her and wept, saying, \"Our beautiful
Snow White is dead!\" For three days and nights
they stood round her, mourning.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_41_html">
	<![CDATA[
At the end of three days, the dwarfs knew they
must bury their beloved Snow White. Yet they
could not bear to do so, for she looked as though
she were still alive.
So they had a glass coffin made, in order that
they might still see her. They wrote on the side, in
letters of gold, that her name was Snow White
and that she was a king\'s daughter. 
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_42_html">
	<![CDATA[
The dwarfs
carried the glass coffin to the top of the
mountain. Then they each took it in turn to sit
always by the coffin, day and night.
There Snow White lay, as if still alive, but
sleeping, with her skin as white as snow, her
cheeks as red as blood and her hair as black as
ebony. Even the birds came and wept to see her
lying so still.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_43_html">
	<![CDATA[
Snow White lay in the glass coffin for many
years and still she looked as if she were alive and
only sleeping.
One day, it happened that a king\'s son found
the glass coffin on the top of the mountain. He
could not take his eyes from the beautiful girl
within it. He gazed at her and fell in love with
her.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_44_html">
	<![CDATA[
\"Let me have the coffin,\" he begged the
dwarfs, \"and I will give you whatever you ask.\"
But they only answered, \"We would not part
with Snow White for all the gold in the world.\"
The Prince continued to plead with them. \"I
cannot live without her\".
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_45_html">
	<![CDATA[
As the Prince\'s servants were carrying the coffin down the mountainside, they stumbled on the roots of a tree. The
coffin was so badly jolted that the piece of apple,
which had stuck in Snow White\'s throat, was
flung out. She opened her eyes, lifted up the lid
of the coffin and sat up. \"Where am I?\" she
cried, in surprise.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_46_html">
	<![CDATA[
The Prince was overjoyed to see her alive. He
told her all that had happened and how he had
fallen in love with her. \"Come with me to my
father\'s palace and we shall be married,\" he
begged, and Snow White agreed.
She said goodbye to the dwarfs who had been
so kind to her and had loved her so dearly.
Although they were sad to lose her, they were
content to know that she was alive and that she
would be happy with the Prince.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_47_html">
	<![CDATA[
A magnificent wedding feast was arranged for
Snow White and the Prince. And it happened
that Snow White\'s stepmother was among those
invited to the feast. When the Queen, dressed in
her finest clothes, was ready for the wedding, she
stood before her mirror and asked

	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_48_html">
	<![CDATA[
The mirror replied,
But the truth I must speak
and so I do vow.
That the young bride-to-be is more
lovely than thou!\"
These words so angered the Queen that, at
first, she felt she could not bear to go to the wedding. Later, she felt she must see this new
young Queen. Of course, when she arrived at the
feast, she recognised Snow White! Her rage was
so great that she fell down and had to be taken
home, where soon afterwards she died.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="snowwhite_page_49_html">
	<![CDATA[
THE END!!!!
	]]>
</string>



</resources>