<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
<string name="taleinorange_page_0_html">
	<![CDATA[
	She was in an orange car\.\.\.with her dad and mom. A strange music
was all around them. You could say it was purple\.\.\.
With tales in red and yellow swimming inside her, tears of joy ran
down her cheeks. When she wiped them, they had become orange\.\.\.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_1_html">
	<![CDATA[
The path they followed connected the Orange State of the Moon with
the Purple Night. It was made out of silk, knit by a bird that long before had
ran away from the seamstress of the palace
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_2_html">
	<![CDATA[
What a confusing dream! She could not understand it. Usually, she was
the one grownups could not understand. Everyone thought her love for
orange was bizarre. Obsession, they called it.
As a baby, her mom said, she got hold of an orange rattle and would not
let go. She only wore orange clothing. She ate only orange food.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_3_html">
	<![CDATA[
She almost drove her parents crazy. They simply could not understand
her. But what else could she do?
Tiptoeing in the dark and quiet house, she went in the kitchen, opened
the refrigerator and looked at the shelves before pulling out a carrot.
Then she filled a glass of orange juice and stepped out onto the balcony.
An orange half-moon leaned into the sky’s background.Tomorrow
they were going on a trip.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_4_html">
	<![CDATA[
The suitcases waited with patience in the hallway for dawn. Hers was
orange-what else?
For the first time in her life she would fly on a plane. For the first time
she would be leaving the country. They were flying to Spain—her dad
showed her on the map and told her stories about poets, painters and
bullfighters. They would rent a car (she picked it out herself on the
Internet and it was a fantastic and shiny orange Volkswagen) and they
would go to magical cities, her mom said. 
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_5_html">
	<![CDATA[
She believed this Lorca –mom\’ s favorite poet- with the most beautiful
gaze she had ever seen, was definitely \“Portokalian\”. For who else could
write such a beautiful song about an orange tree?
\“Underneath the orange tree she washes the cottons
Green are her eyes and her voice purple\”
Why did her mother\’s eyes cloud over when she heard the song, and why
did her dad always squeeze her hand?
Marianna drank her last drop, looked at the moon one more time and
went to sleep.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_6_html">
	<![CDATA[
Inside the airplane, Marianna could not stop gazing and asking
questions. As the plane rose to the air, the earth grew smaller and smaller.
He pointed to a rock down below, \“Hump\” as they called it because of the
way it was shaped like a hump on top of the mountain. Under its shadow
people were diving from the rocks only to resurface from the ladder to do
it all over again
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_7_html">
	<![CDATA[
Marianna found herself fascinated with the tray table that was popping
up and down. She was also fascinated with the orange juice, that the
stewardess had given her. She was really pretty and spoke with a funny
accent, like her friend Jason. Then she gave her a toy-an airplane with
yellow and red colors: \“the flag of Spain\”, mom told her. If you mix red with
yellow you get orange!
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_8_html">
	<![CDATA[
\“Spanish women are beautiful\”, said dad, looking at the stewardess. Her
mom blushed and did not say anything. Marianna played dumb. She did not
say anything either but she agreed with her dad!
She liked everything: even the unbelievable food. The paella was orange
and delicious. Maybe Spain is a part of Portokalia? Somewhere in Gibraltar
Hercules had discovered \“golden apples from the Garden of the
Hesperides\”, namely the oranges! Orange is her second favorite fruit – first
is tangerine
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_9_html">
	<![CDATA[
She pulled out of her orange bag her coloring pencils and created her
drawing of Portokalia. A country that you could drink with a straw and it
would rain tangerines and oranges. And the white boats that would take
off from her harbor and come back loaded with clams and sea urchins. They
had the smell of the sea when opened on the plate, an orange explosion.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_10_html">
	<![CDATA[
The straw from the drawing grew. Marianna felt like it was sucking her in
and all of a sudden she found herself flowing inside it like a waterslide. She
was scared but most of all she was having fun. She was flowing madly. The
smell of tangerine became clearer as she got further down. Like when she
would open with her fingers a jar of her favorite tangerines from Chio and
the smell swam in her nostrils. Little drops splash you and you shiver with
delight.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_11_html">
	<![CDATA[
She was flowing like Alice in Wonderland! She expected to see a white
rabbit run in front of her at any moment. But she was living her own
Fairytale-and without realizing it-she was in a sky full of tangerines. She
was flying on the tops of some strange orange trees and open books that
were flying too for the distant horizon.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_12_html">
	<![CDATA[
She caught sight of some of the titles: \“Tangerine Jelly\”, \“Clockwork
Orange\”, \“Bitter Orange\”, \“My other half of orange\”, \“5/4 orange\”,
\“Tangerine Days\”…
She swoops down next to a tower in the shape of a glass which
overlooks the cliffs of a foamed orange juice that runs down like the sea
and hits on the sandy beach.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_13_html">
	<![CDATA[
She fell in too making a giant Splash! Her mouth was full of sweet and
sour juice\.\.\.with quick strokes she reached the shore. In front of her a
road leads straight to the Orange Tower.
An orange carpet rolled out in front of her feet. She hesitated
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_14_html">
	<![CDATA[
\“Come now, do not be afraid. We \‘ve been waiting for you!\”
An orange tiger, dressed in a green velvet suit, yellow boots with blue
dots and a huge red bow tie stood before her.
The tiger gently bowed down and showed her the way.
Marianna started walking on the carpet
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_15_html">
	<![CDATA[
Marianna hesitated a little and the tiger gently lead her by the hand
to the colorful entrance of the Orange Tower. On top of the gate, one
giant and juicy orange slice sends out waves of its refreshing aroma.
Freshly squeezed orange juice in enormous jugs and glasses, foamed
around her. 
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_16_html">
	<![CDATA[
Small orange drops sprayed her as she crossed the entrance
into the hallway with the strangest paintings of oranges. She lost herself
in the designs and colors that she did not see the tiger disappear.
Still in a daze, she heard a sweet and melancholic song coming from the
sky.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_17_html">
	<![CDATA[
\“I open the closet and in the mirror I see a child smiling at me and telling me:
\“I have been grounded. But if you want to keep coming over the glass is your door.
They cannot see me,
And when I say orange three times, come out\”
Marianna looks up. A woman with a yellow blouse and blue skirt, holding
a big flower in her hand, sang.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_18_html">
	<![CDATA[
She looked at Marianna when she realized she was being watched and
said:
\“Welcome. It\’s nice to see you here the first day of the month!”
\“But it’s not the first day of the month\”, answered Marianna…
\“Here every day is the first day of the month! We have thousands of names
for the months. We name them as we please. Do you have any idea what is
the name for today\’s month
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_19_html">
	<![CDATA[
Let\’s call it Marianna-isn\’t that your name? I
do not think Lucia got it wrong. Who is Lucia you are wondering\.\.\. the
stewardess! Oh, don\’t look at me like that! Surprised you, didn\’t I? She
chooses who comes to Portokalia. Do not think we welcome just anyone!”
Marianna was dizzy. The woman kept flying over her head and not even
once did she stop to take a breath.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_20_html">
	<![CDATA[
\“Don\’t be scared\”, she continued, unfazed, \“No one will notice that you
are missing! I, Isabella, named after the old Queen, am telling you. Have
you seen the play? Which play? The play: Isabella, three caravels and a
storyteller. It has some good songs as well. Have you heard the Oyster and
the pearl? My mom used to sing it to me so I could fall asleep\”.
She started to sing, so sweetly, that Marianna forgot how dizzy she was.
She felt her feet leave the ground as she was climbing skyward in between
foaming oranges:
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_21_html">
	<![CDATA[
The young son from Tunezi,
Black like the seabed\’s oyster,
He who got caught in love\’s net,
He had an eye, eye, eye,
He had an eye like agate
He who got caught in love\’s net,
That got caught in love\’s net,
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_22_html">
	<![CDATA[
White, whiter than dawn,
Leonora, daughter from Castille,
Her skin a magnolia flower,
Her ear like a shell,
In love\’s net she got caught as well,
In his love\’s net she got caught as well,
The young son from Tunezi
Black like the seabed\’s oyster,
Becomes pale whenever he sees her,
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_23_html">
	<![CDATA[
The oyster opens up, opens gently
Capturing her inside,
White, whiter than the dawn,
With trembling lips,
She kisses him sweetly
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_24_html">
	<![CDATA[
\“I will not sing anymore,\” Isabella said, flying around her. \“It\’s much too sad.
If I continue, I will not stop crying. And I see you were about to cry as
well. Your heart needs to be light in order for you to fly next to me. Come,
do not be afraid. Take my hand! Portokalia waits!\”
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_25_html">
	<![CDATA[
Isabella would not stop singing as Marianna held on to her hand in a
tight grip while they were flying over Portokalia. The houses did not have
roofs and Marianna could see what was going on inside. Children playing,
moms and dads cooking, some were reading and others were kissing. None
of them had television!
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_26_html">
	<![CDATA[
\“We put them away when the sun comes out! Sunlight goes in and cleans
them. It\’s like living in the country. When it rains we put the roofs back in.
It never snows here-the phrase \“white as snow\” we read in books, is
inconceivable here. Some folks let the rain in. Instead of a floor they like
green grass in their rooms. They only cover the furniture when it rains.
This idea, the \“portable roof\” was discovered by my great-great
grandfather, who was none other than the greatest inventor in Portokalia:
Juan Ramon Louis Bertrand!
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_27_html">
	<![CDATA[
 He was the first who made the towers out of
orange juice and no matter how much you drink it never finishes. He
discovered the flying books that you can read while flying. The wallet with
the orange-money that never runs out, also the machine that turns
kumquat seeds in jam in three minutes. The memory machine for names
that you forget, and the apricot ice cream with the almonds!And finally, the
orange dessert! Take a piece of paper and write down the recipe: It will
blow your mind! You don\’t have a pencil? Watch me! Pencil-paper, come!\”
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_28_html">
	<![CDATA[
Ingredients:
 6 bottles of still orange juice,
3 sachets of powdered cream,
3 table spoons of sugar,
1 pack of Miranda biscuits,
almond or hazelnut threshed
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_29_html">
	<![CDATA[
Heat the orange juice and stir with
powdered cream and sugar. Leave to
cool.
 Spread in a clear pan a layer of biscuits.
Pour in half the cream. We spread
another layer of biscuits. We pour the
rest of the cream. Optionally, we may
put on top threshed hazelnut or
almond. Leave in the refrigerator for
two-three hours.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_30_html">
	<![CDATA[
The pencil was writing with great speed and perfect grammar. As
soon as the recipe was written down, Isabella folded the paper and handed
it to Marianna.
\“This is my mother\’s recipe. The pencil-paper that write on command, is my
great-great grandfather\’s invention! He won Portokalia\’s greatest award
for that: 3000 children\’s smiles. Now look down! 
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_31_html">
	<![CDATA[
You\’ll see one more of my
great-great grandfather\’s inventions. A piano-typewriter! He received the
Union Composers Authors of PortokaliaAward for it.
The truth is that he discovered it for a writer he felt unrequited love formy great-great grandmother. He would send her presents and make her
promises, but she remained rigid.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_32_html">
	<![CDATA[
Until the day he made the piano-typewriter. She then realized that no one
would love her more. They lived together from then on, but she never
wrote on the piano-typewriter. She told him that she did not want him to
think that she only married him for the magical piano-typewriter. It was
enough for her that he made it, showing her his love.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_33_html">
	<![CDATA[
The piano-typewriter stayed in the sitting-room, unused-a sample of
their love. The first person who dared to touch it was Maria-Louisa
Korvalan-my mother and much loved writer of children\’s books of Portokalia.
There she is now!
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_34_html">
	<![CDATA[
Oh Greece, it is such a magical country! We had gone with your father
before you were born. To the prettiest cave I have ever seen. With all
those colors. Oh hello Marianna. Would you like some tangerine juice? I
brought the tangerine tree from an island that starts with the letter C,
four letters
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_35_html">
	<![CDATA[
The writer, is a woman that words and stories live inside of her. When we
met her she was wearing flowers for rings and blue heels. She said, with
those heels she would travel to the clouds whenever she got bored in
Portokalia. She liked to drink dream coffees with a colorful friend. They
often do favors for one another.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_36_html">
	<![CDATA[
Oh Greece, it is such a magical country! We had gone with your father
before you were born. To the prettiest cave I have ever seen. With all
those colors. Oh hello Marianna. Would you like some tangerine juice? I
brought the tangerine tree from an island that starts with the letter C,
four letters
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_37_html">
	<![CDATA[
The writer, is a woman that words and stories live inside of her. When we
met her she was wearing flowers for rings and blue heels. She said, with
those heels she would travel to the clouds whenever she got bored in
Portokalia. She liked to drink dream coffees with a colorful friend. They
often do favors for one another.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_38_html">
	<![CDATA[
Oh Greece, it is such a magical country! We had gone with your father
before you were born. To the prettiest cave I have ever seen. With all
those colors. Oh hello Marianna. Would you like some tangerine juice? I
brought the tangerine tree from an island that starts with the letter C,
four letters
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_39_html">
	<![CDATA[
The writer, is a woman that words and stories live inside of her. When we
met her she was wearing flowers for rings and blue heels. She said, with
those heels she would travel to the clouds whenever she got bored in
Portokalia. She liked to drink dream coffees with a colorful friend. They
often do favors for one another.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_40_html">
	<![CDATA[
Oh Greece, it is such a magical country! We had gone with your father
before you were born. To the prettiest cave I have ever seen. With all
those colors. Oh hello Marianna. Would you like some tangerine juice? I
brought the tangerine tree from an island that starts with the letter C,
four letters
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_41_html">
	<![CDATA[
Oh Greece, it is such a magical country! We had gone with your father
before you were born. To the prettiest cave I have ever seen. With all
those colors. Oh hello Marianna. Would you like some tangerine juice? I
brought the tangerine tree from an island that starts with the letter C,
four letters
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_42_html">
	<![CDATA[
The writer, is a woman that words and stories live inside of her. When we
met her she was wearing flowers for rings and blue heels. She said, with
those heels she would travel to the clouds whenever she got bored in
Portokalia. She liked to drink dream coffees with a colorful friend. They
often do favors for one another.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_43_html">
	<![CDATA[
Oh Greece, it is such a magical country! We had gone with your father
before you were born. To the prettiest cave I have ever seen. With all
those colors. Oh hello Marianna. Would you like some tangerine juice? I
brought the tangerine tree from an island that starts with the letter C,
four letters
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_44_html">
	<![CDATA[
Oh Greece, it is such a magical country! We had gone with your father
before you were born. To the prettiest cave I have ever seen. With all
those colors. Oh hello Marianna. Would you like some tangerine juice? I
brought the tangerine tree from an island that starts with the letter C,
four letters
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_45_html">
	<![CDATA[
Oh Greece, it is such a magical country! We had gone with your father
before you were born. To the prettiest cave I have ever seen. With all
those colors. Oh hello Marianna. Would you like some tangerine juice? I
brought the tangerine tree from an island that starts with the letter C,
four letters
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_46_html">
	<![CDATA[
The writer, is a woman that words and stories live inside of her. When we
met her she was wearing flowers for rings and blue heels. She said, with
those heels she would travel to the clouds whenever she got bored in
Portokalia. She liked to drink dream coffees with a colorful friend. They
often do favors for one another.
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_47_html">
	<![CDATA[
Oh Greece, it is such a magical country! We had gone with your father
before you were born. To the prettiest cave I have ever seen. With all
those colors. Oh hello Marianna. Would you like some tangerine juice? I
brought the tangerine tree from an island that starts with the letter C,
four letters
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_48_html">
	<![CDATA[
Oh Greece, it is such a magical country! We had gone with your father
before you were born. To the prettiest cave I have ever seen. With all
those colors. Oh hello Marianna. Would you like some tangerine juice? I
brought the tangerine tree from an island that starts with the letter C,
four letters
	]]>
</string>

<string name="taleinorange_page_49_html">
	<![CDATA[
The writer, is a woman that words and stories live inside of her. When we
met her she was wearing flowers for rings and blue heels. She said, with
those heels she would travel to the clouds whenever she got bored in
Portokalia. She liked to drink dream coffees with a colorful friend. They
often do favors for one another.
	]]>
</string>
</resources>